気がつけば 地の底の底
Kaiji came to in an underground slave labor facility.
強制労働施設に
放り込まれたカイジ
His only hope for escape, a one-day furlough pass.
脱出する唯一の希望は１日外出券
そんなカイジの前に立つ この男
班長 大槻
And now his team leader, Ohtsuki, stands before him.
どうだい 今夜あたり
こいつで復活ってえのは？
How about it? Why not get back to your old habits tonight?
A devil beckons from the abyss! The dice game chinchirorin!
悪魔が誘うサイコロ賭博
チンチロリン
The Rules of the Game
Kaiji, you're supposed to be great at this, aren't you?
カイジ君は すご腕なんだろ？
噂じゃ ここの大幹部を倒したとか
I heard you took down the big shot,
１億円 張ったとかさ
関係ねえって
and that you toss a hundred million yen around like it's nothing.
Doesn't matter. I lost in the end, and that's why I'm here now.
結局 負けて
こんな所にいるようじゃ
大バカ野郎も いいとこだ
I'm a damned fool.
Even if you're a fool, look who you're comparing yourself with.
いや 仮にバカだとしても
スケールが違う
ここの連中ときたら
スケールの小さい奴ばかりでよ
These guys are all small fries.
You'll never get anywhere playing them for matchsticks.
せっかく勝負しても
チマチマ張ってばかりで
全然 胸が高まらない
I mean, I'm in charge here, so as long as everyone's having fun, that's good enough.
まあ 班長としては
皆が楽しんでくれれば
それはそれで いいんだが
本音を言えば
もっと熱い勝負がしたいわけよ
But to be honest, I really want to put more on the line.
カイジ君みたいな男と
Up against someone like you!
いや もちろんカイジ君とわしじゃ
格が違うんだから
Honestly, you're way out of my league, but...
こちらとしては当然
胸を借りるつもりなんだけど
頼むよ こいつでさ
C'mon! You can bet this!
６万借りても倍の12にすりゃ
いいだけの話じゃない な？
Even if you have to borrow sixty thou, everyone'll be happy if you turn it into one-twenty.
バカ野郎
その倍が簡単にできりゃ…
Fool! Is that all you think I can do with that?
じゃ こうしよう
How about this?
普段は６万借りたら
結果はどうあれ 返す時には
If you waited until payday, you'd have to pay me back ninety thousand.
正規の給料分９万で返すのが
決まりなんだが
今回は特別 今夜中に返せば
But if you pay me back the sixty tonight, we're even.
チャラってことにしよう
チャラ？
Even?
If he doubles it to 120,000, he can easily pay back the advance.
倍の12万に増やせば
６万返して前借りは清算
手元には６万が残り
今月をしのげる
He'd be left with 60,000 for the month.
これさ これが今
カイジ君が体勢を立て直す
See, this is the best way to set yourself up with a stack.
ベストな方法じゃないかな
チッ　おだてたり すかしたり
この班長 意外に食えねえな
Buttering me up and making a show of things... This guy's sharp.
だが確かに そうかも
But, he may be right.
このまま400ぽっちを手に
禁欲生活を送ったら
If I starve myself by trying to live on four hundred in pocket change,
I'll blow it all again the next payday.
また給料日には
爆発しちまいそうだ
And if I borrow that money and win tonight's game...
それより その金を借りて
今日のｷﾞｬﾝﾌﾞﾙで少しでも勝てば
むろん負けたら
更に最悪な状況に追い込まれる
But if I lose, then I'm really fucked.
しかし相手は あの利根川や
会長のような猛者とは
Then again, they're nowhere near as serious as Tonegawa or the President...
ほど遠い連中
こんな連中に俺が負けるか？
Is it even possible for me to lose against them?
負けるわけがねえ
No way.
今夜中に返せば６でいいんだな？
It's sixty thousand if I pay you back tonight, right?
On my honor.
わしも男だ　二言はない
開いてくれ
おお そうこなくっちゃ
Hand it over, then.
You didn't even need to ask.
Gambling is officially banned.
基本的には賭博は御法度
だが就労者の
ガス抜きの意味もあり
But, in order to allow the workers to let off steam,
各班の班長が
責任を持つことを条件に
the leaders of each team, if they accept responsibility for the consequences,
月に２～３回の開帳が認められる
are allowed two or three gaming nights a month.
大槻 今宵の賭博開帳の許可を得る
Ohtsuki has received permission to hold a gambling night.
ようし 開帳だ
All right, it's time.
Hey, Isawa, Numakawa! Get everything ready!
おい 石和 沼川　準備しろ
はい
お…
Okay!
負けねえ こんな連中に
I won't lose.
Not to these guys.
負けるはずがねえ
I can't lose.
通常 ９時半には消灯
Normally, lights out is at 9:30 sharp.
だが場を開く部屋は
But in rooms where gambling is taking place, this is extended to 11:30.
特別に11時半まで
消灯延長が許される
参加者は両替後
参加費300ペリカを支払い
The participants, after making change,
buy into the game for 300 perica,
おのおの好きな席に着く
and then take their seats.
Twice a month, on the first and third Saturdays,
月に２回 第１第３土曜に
開かれる場では
他の班からも大人数が参加する
members of other teams are allowed to participate.
But as tonight's games were called on short notice,
…が 今夜の集まりは
急きょ 決まったもの
集まりは小規模
few are in attendance.
All right, we've got two new players tonight.
さて今夜は初参加が２人
カイジ君と三好君だ
Kaiji and Miyoshi.
２人はチンチロの経験は？
一応 何回か
Have either of you ever played chinchiro?
A few times.
僕は実は一度も…
Just... Just once.
まったくの初心者で… すいません
Sorry, I'm pretty new at this...
いいさ いいさ
それじゃ簡単に説明しよう
No worries. Let me explain the rules.
To play chinchiro, you roll three dice in a bowl.
チンチロってのは サイコロを３つ
どんぶりに投げ込んで
出た目で勝ち負けが決まる
Your roll decides whether you win or lose.
サイコロを振るのは
１人３回まで
Each person can roll the dice up to three times. Simple, isn't it?
簡単だろ？
はあ
一番最初に親が振る
The dealer rolls first.
それから左回りで順番に子が振る
Then the players, in clockwise order.
親と子 どちらの目が強いかで
金が行き来する
Whoever has the best roll between the dealer and the other players takes the pot.
So it's a game in which each player is up against the dealer.
いわば親対子の勝負ってわけだ
で こいつが目の強い順番だ
And here's how you tell which roll wins.
チンチロの出目とは
A chinchiro roll is the value of the third die after the other two come up a pair.
３つのサイコロのうち
２つの同じ目を出して
初めて目として成立する
２つの目が２　そして残りが１
If two dice come up 2 and the last comes up 1...
この場合は出目が１
The player has rolled a 1.
If this happens, they've rolled a 6.
この場合は６
出目の順位は
６が最も強く １が弱い目
Of the rolls, 6 is thestrongest, 1 is the weakest.
当然 強い目を出した者が勝者
張った分の金額を得る
The man with the highest roll wins.
He takes the pot.
３つの目がバラバラの状態
If all the dice come up differently,
これを目なしと呼ぶ
it's a bust.
この場合 ３回まで
サイコロを振ることができるが
In this case, the player can roll up to three times,
３回振って目なしなら負けが確定
but three busts in a row are an automatic loss.
張った金を失うことになる
They then lose their bet.
ただし この３つのﾊﾞﾗﾊﾞﾗの目にも
２つ特例がある
But there are two special rules on unmatched numbers,
シゴロ
この目が出た時は２倍づけ
4, 5, and 6.
A player who rolls this wins double their bet.
Twice the money they'd wagered.
すなわち張った金額の倍を得る
On the other hand, a 1, 2, and 3.
逆にヒフミ
この目が出た場合は倍払い
A player who rolls this loses double their bet.
すなわち張った金額の
２倍を払うことになる
Also twice the money they'd wagered.
And the strongest roll...
そして最も強い出目
is this.
それがこいつ　ゾロ目だ
Three of a kind.
ここじゃ
２から６のゾロ目が３倍づけ
Triples of 2 through 6 win triple the bet.
更に１の目
And then, triple 1s...
Snake eyes win five times the original wager.
このピンゾロは
５倍づけってことになる
Five times!?
ご… ５倍
ハハハ そんなにビビらなくても
そうそう出る目じゃないさ
Don't worry about it.
They don't come up that often.
もう１つ ションベンといって
And then there's the "pisser."
こんなふうにサイコロが
こぼれた場合
If a die rolls out of the bowl, we treat it as a bust.
うちでは目なしと決めている
Even if the dealer rolls a bust, if the player rolls a pisser he loses.
たとえ親が目なしでも
子がションベンすれば親の勝ちだ
そしてションベンを出した時点で
次はサイコロを振れない
And if you roll a pisser, you're not allowed to reroll.
最初にこぼしたら
あとの２回は振れないってわけだ
Do it on your first try, and your other two are forfeit.
さて ここからが肝心なんだが
And last, but not least...
うちのチンチロには
３つの特殊ルールがある
We have three special rules down here.
特殊ルール？
Special rules?
They're nothing really special.
それほど大げさなもんじゃないが
ルールの付け足しってところだ
Just a few tweaks.
特殊ルールその１
親の総取りはなし
Special rule number one!
The dealer can't win automatically.
Normally, when the dealer rolls a 6, a 4-5-6, or triples, they automatically win.
通常 親が振って
出目６やシゴロ ゾロ目を出せば
その時点で親の勝ち
They receive everyone's bet.
金は親の総取りとなる
しかし地下チンチロでは
But in underground chinchirorin, no matter the dealer's roll, the players can attempt to beat it.
親がどんなに
それら強い目を出しても
子はサイコロを振ることができる
If the dealer rolls a 6, the player can force a draw by doing the same.
仮に親が出目６を出しても
子が同じ６を出せば引き分け
シゴロやゾロ目を出せば
逆に子の勝ちということになる
If he rolls 4-5-6 or triples, he could even win.
みんな苦しい中 ギリギリの金で
遊んでいるんだから
I know none of you have much money to spare,
親の総取りは あっけないし
あんまりだってことでな
so it's just unfair for the dealer to take all.
On the other hand, even if the dealer rolls 1-2-3, it's a draw if the player rolls a pisser.
逆に親が
倍払いのヒフミを出しても
子がションベンなら分け
親の総払いもなしってわけだ
The dealer doesn't have to pay.
特殊ルールその２
親はスルーできる
Special rule number two!
The dealer can pass!
Can pass?
スルーできる？
Passing. If he feels like he doesn't have enough money or the dice aren't on his side,
スルー　すなわち
金に余裕がなかったり 自分の目が
下がっていると思ったら
親をパスすることができる
the dealer can pass.
Of course, he's welcome to play as usual the next time it's his turn.
もちろん１度パスしても
次に順番が回った時
受けるかどうか
それも自由だ　オッケーかな？
Okay?
Sure.
Special rule number three!
特殊ルールその３
親を続けられるのは２回まで
２回？
Turns as dealer last only two rounds!
Two rounds?
親のバカ勝ちを避けるため
親は２回まで
To keep the dealer from taking everyone to the cleaners,
each player is only dealer twice in a row.
次の隣の者に
親が移るというシステム
Afterwards, the next player in the sequence is dealer.
ただし親が１発目に
目なしや１の目を出したら即交代
But if the dealer rolls a bust or a 1 on his first turn, it changes immediately.
１回交代もあり得る
ああ
So it can change after a round, too.
Okay.
Oh, and there's a bet restriction of twenty thousand.
それと賭けの上限は２万まで
２万…
Twenty?
それ以上ドカドカ張られたら
親が持たねえんだよ
Wouldn't want to break the bank, now, would we?
なるほど
だが親が受けるというなら別
I see.
This is at the dealer's discretion, though.
上限なしだ
So it's not really a limit.
If you want to risk it all, just wait until I'm dealer.
大きく張りたくなったら
わしの親の時に来るがいい
I'll take that bet.
わしは受けてやるぞ
No matter how high.
いくらでも
いや チビチビいきますよ
しばらくは
Nah...
I'll keep it low for now.
フフフ　そりゃ当然
最初からバカ張りはできんよな
Oh, of course.
You can't go all in at the beginning.
さて
Anyways...
そろそろ参ろうか
Shall we begin?
地下チンチロ 開始
Underground chinchiro...
Begin!
さあ 張った 張った
Place your bets!
In underground chinchiro,
地下チンチロ　通例として
班長大槻の親から始まる
the team leader, Ohtsuki, usually goes first.
カイジ　張りは100ペリカ
Kaiji bets 100 perica.
最初は様子見だ
First, I'm going to see how it goes.
Take it easy and wait.
ユルユルいって待つ
強く張れる その機を
Wait for the moment to strike...
大槻 １投目
Ohtsuki's first roll!
A 5!
出目は５
初っ端から悪いな 皆の衆
Looks like you gentlemen are out of luck.
何やってんだ
いや 出目をメモして…
What are you doing?
Oh, just writing down your roll...
野暮なことするなよ
あ… はあ
Knock it off, you idiot!
まあまあ　いいじゃないか
楽しみ方は人それぞれだ
Cool it.
Don't worry about it. Everyone has their own way of having fun.
いや しかし…
好きにしな
But...
Do whatever you want.
あ… ありがとうございます
Thanks.
Here, your turn.
ほれ　お前の番だ
はあ　まあ班長さえよければ
俺は別に
If you say so.
続いて子の１番手 沼川
Next, the first player, Numakawa!
He rolls 1-2-3 and pays double!
ヒフミ　倍払い
あっちゃー！
ツいてないのう
Aw shit!
It's just not your day, is it?
やった
All right!
そして来る
And it arrives!
カイジの初振り
Kaiji's first turn!
その１投目
And his first roll!
なんと初っ端でシゴロ
Amazingly, it comes up 4-5-6 on his first roll!
さすが カイジ君　参ったな
Wow, you really are the Kaiji.
でも助かったよ 張りが100で
Guess I'm lucky you bet so low.
あれ？シゴロは倍づけで200
１枚余分じゃ？
Hm, 4-5-6 is double, so I get 200.
You gave me one too many.
せっかくのシゴロだってのに
張りが100じゃかわいそうだ
You deserve better than a bet of 100 for a leadoff 4-5-6 will earn you.
Take it. As a consolation prize.
１枚は残念賞　取っておきな
どうも
Thanks.
なになに　さあ次は三好君だ
Huh?
Anyways, your turn, Miyoshi.
は… はい
Okay...
ハア　残念賞か　確かにそうだ
Consolation prize, huh? I guess.
せっかくの倍づけも
張りが100じゃな
Even if it's double, it's still only two hundreds.
いや まだ流れも見えない１投目だ
仕方ない
But... I can't read the table yet. Oh, well.
それに この振りは
勝負の肝じゃない
Plus, this isn't the real meat of the game.
このチンチロは親対子の勝負
Chinchirorin is a game played against the dealer.
親で いかに勝つか
When you're the dealer, you can win it all.
それっ　あー！
逆に言えば親の時
いかに負けないか　そこが肝
But it's vital to not lose.
That's the meat of the game.
このチンチロを制するカギ
急所だ
That's the key to winning at chinchirorin.
待つんだ 辛抱強く 流れを
Wait... Wait patiently for the flow...
しかし一進一退
But as the game continues,
Kaiji cannot feel the flow!
カイジには流れが感じられない
意識がぼやけている
He begins to lose focus...
当然 張りが100では意識が希薄
Of course!
Betting hundred by hundred is not enough to hold his attention!
流れなど感じられるはずもない
It's impossible for him to feel the flow like this!
この少額の張りでは
勝った時に うれしさより
With these tiny sums, a win brings not joy, but disappointment!
むしろガッカリ 落胆
惜しいという気持ちが大きい
His regret grows!
逆に負けると どこかホッとする
Even a loss would be a relief!
通常のギャンブルの思考と逆
言い換えれば
It's the opposite of normal gambling...
The sensations of a normal game are gone!
ギャンブルにおける正常な感覚
生理から離れてしまっている
そんなことで熱を 勢いを
The passion... The spirit...
あるいは幸運の兆し 気配 兆候を
The feel of Lady Luck's gaze, the atmosphere, the little signs...
感じられるはずがないのだ
He can feel nothing!
開始から40分
カイジ ようやく己の愚に気づく
40 minutes after the game begins, Kaiji realizes his folly!
バカか 俺は　賢明ぶりやがって
Am I a fool for trying to outsmart them?
ムダな張りをしねえとか
これじゃダメなんだ
I'm wasting my time with these tiny bets!
小さく張った時は負けて
Lose small and win big, right?
大きく張った時に勝つ？
おいおい
そりゃ それが博打の理想
That's the gambler's ideal, isn't it?
だが理想であって基本じゃない
But it's the ideal, not how it actually works!
ギャンブルとは
もっと泥仕合 愚かなもの
Gambling is dirtier than that.
Fool!
It doesn't work without a twinge of pain!
ヒリつかなきゃダメなんだ
３度勝てば顔は紅潮し
体温は上がる
If he wins three times, his face glows and his temperature rises!
逆に３度負けたら血が逆流
But if he loses three times, his blood freezes in his veins!
それがギャンブルの張りの基本
That is the truth of betting!
そんな張りを続けてこそ
ほの見える分岐点
His wagers bring him to the crossroads!
流れが変わる時
When the flow changes, he can feel the waves of fortune lapping at his feet!
強運の波動 熱く張れる場所を
感じられるのだ
もうやめだ ケチな勝負は
I'm done playing around.
親 あんたの番だぜ
Oh really?
It's your turn.
スルーだ
え？
I pass.
俺には まだ流れが
まるで見えていない
I still can't really feel the flow.
ここで親を受けるのは早い
It's too soon to play the dealer.
何 固まってんだよ
え？
Who put the stick up your ass?
どうせ お前も親はスルーだろ？
いや その…
What, you gonna pass, too?
Well, um...
ここまで一度も受けてないしな
You haven't laid a single bet.
いや でも
やってみようかな 今回は
I guess I'll give it a try.
そうそう　ﾁﾝﾁﾛは親を受けてこそ
だいご味を味わえるんだ
Yeah. Playing dealer is the best part of chinchirorin.
やったほうがいいぞ
Go for it!
All right, here goes.
それじゃやります
さあ皆の衆　三好君の初親だ
張った 張った
Okay, gentlemen! It's Miyoshi's first turn as dealer!
Place your bets!
え… えー！3000ペリカ？
3,000 perica!?
ほう
どうして　今までずっと
100ペリカだったのにどうして
Why!?
You've been betting 100 all this time! Why!?
ねえ どうして？ねえ？
Come on, why? Why!?
うるせえ！博打に
どうしてこうしてがあるか
Shut up! There's no "why" in gambling!
張る時は張るんだよ
そんな…
You just lay your money down!
Man...
まあまあ三好君　なにも
取られると決まったわけじゃない
There, there, Miyoshi. You haven't lost yet.
案外 大儲けするかもしれないよ
You might do better than you think.
そりゃそうだけど
さあ振って振って
I guess...
Go ahead and roll.
でも何だかな…
But...
I dunno...
よりによって１かよ
よし
Aww man, a 1?
All right!
In normal chinchiro, if the house rolls a 1, the players win automatically.
通常チンチロは
親が１の目を出すと
子は振ることなしに勝ち
親の総払いとなるが
The dealer pays out to everyone.
この地下チンチロでは
親の目にかかわらず
But in underground chinchiro, the players roll no matter what!
子は必ず振る
よっしゃ
しかし親の目が１であれば
All right!
If the dealer rolls a 1, they're likely to win.
大抵の場合は勝てる
Seven players sit between Miyoshi and Kaiji.
結局 三好は
カイジに回るまでの７人のうち
目の出なかった大槻以外に全敗
Miyoshi loses to each of them except for Ohtsuki's roll of no dice.
とはいえ ここまでは
皆 張りが小さい
But everyone else's bet has been low.
問題は3000を張ったカイジ
His worry is Kaiji, who bet 3,000!
このカイジに勝ちさえすれば
ここまでの負けは帳消し
If he beats Kaiji, he'll win back his losses, and more!
釣りが出る
悪いな 三好
Sorry, Miyoshi.
誰かが泣かなきゃならないのが
ギャンブル
In gambling, someone must always lose.
ここはお前が泣く番だ
And this is your turn to lose.
Kaiji rolls!
カイジ １投目
目は出ず
No dice!
Oh, yeah, you're going to lose.
泣いてもらうぜ 三好
All right!
え？
またも目なし
No dice again!
あ… バカな　よりによって
ここで目が出ないなんて
Impossible... No dice again?
No way! You're shitting me!
あるわけねえ　ふざけるな
あるわけねえ！
No fucking way!
カイジ 運命の３投目
Kaiji makes his fateful third roll!
俺が負けるわけがねえ
I can't lose!
負けるはずがないんだ
It's impossible!
やるな カイジ君
Wow, Kaiji.
ここでこの目は なかなか出せんぞ
That almost never comes up.
Kaiji's third roll...
カイジ ３投目
あろうことかヒフミ
Is, of all things, 1-2-3!
倍払い
ウッソー！
He pays double!
やった
Awesome!
大張りで最悪の目
The worst roll possible!
A tremendous reversal of fate, possible only in underground chinchiro!
この地下チンチロゆえに起きた
大逆転
カイジ 6000の払い
Kaiji pays out 6,000!
どうも　じゃ失礼して
If I may...
悔しい
I hate it...
悔しい！
He hates it!
悔しい
悔しい！
I hate it...
He hates it!
だが これでいい
But it's enough!
これだ　これでこそ博打
ギャンブルなんだ
This is it...
This is the game!
This is gambling!
忘れてた この感覚
I'd forgotten this feeling...
この悔しさ 憤り 血の逆流
This bitterness!
This rage, this chill in my veins!
さあ次だ　張った 張った
Okay, next round! Place your bets!
いけ！
Go.
Go!
いけ！飛び込め！
Dive in!
飛び込んで いっそ翻弄されろ
Dive in! Even the crashing of the waves is an improvement!
カイジ 覚醒！張り続ける
Kaiji awakens!
He will continue betting!
勝っても負けても張りは3000
Win or lose, he will bet 3,000!
3000…
Three thousand!
3000！
Gambling is...
Dirtier than that.
Fool.
It doesn't work without a twinge of pain!
Tobaku Hakairoku Kaiji: Chinchiro in Hades vol. 1,
from the Underground Slave Labor arc, is now on sale.